<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<!--  
  
We're sorry, but your web browser does not include an integrated RSS reader.  
To be able to subscribe to any of the RSS feeds from the California State Library website, you will need to either:

	1.) Upgrade your web browser or
	2.) Use a RSS aggregator  
	
There are several web browsers which include integrated RSS readers.  These browsers include:

	1.) Internet Explorer 7 (or later)
	2.) Mozilla Firefox 2.0 (or later)
	3.) Opera 7.5 (or later)

There are also many RSS readers which can be used.  A few RSS readers include:

	1.) Bloglines
	2.) Feedmarker
	3.) NewsGator 

-->  
<channel>
    <title>California Research Bureau Reports</title>
    <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/CRBReports.html</link>
    <description>The California Research Bureau (CRB) provides nonpartisan research services to the Governor and his staff, to both houses of the legislature, and to other state elected officials.
	</description>
  <item>
    <title>Programs and Projects Related to Mexico in California State Government – 2017 Update</title>
    <pubDate>Mon, 6 Nov 2017 02:08:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>California Research Bureau (November, 2017). This publication is an update of a 2004 report that identified California government activities related to issues of common interest and concern to California and Mexico. The survey describes over 100 programs operated by dozens of California state departments, agencies, boards and commissions.
  </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/17/ProgramsAndProjectsRelatedToMexicoInCAStateGovt-2017UpdateFINAL.pdf</link>
    </item>
   <item>
    <title>California Policymaking For Tomorrow Amid Rapid Technological Change Today, Video (1:18:05)</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 5 Apr 2017 11:54:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Three experts discuss the impact of rapid technological change on California's economy and jobs, as well as the opportunities, challenges and risks awaiting California policymakers. Anne Neville, director of the California Research Bureau, moderates a thought-provoking discussion with Nicholas Davis, head of Society and Innovation at the World Economic Forum in Geneva; Rachel Hatch, research director of the 10-Year Forecast at the Institute for the Future in Palo Alto; and California's chief economist, Irena Asmundson. 
  </description>
  <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DOCMOcaYlWI</link>
    </item>
  <item>
    <title>Frivolous Action Filings in California Courts</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 9:30:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>California enacted Assembly Bill 2494 (2014) to expand the legal remedies available against frivolous litigation. Specifically, the statute revived California Code of Civil Procedure section 128.5, which allows parties in lawsuits to file motions requesting sanctions against bad faith legal actions. This report, mandated by AB 2494, examines the statute's impact in the first two years after passage on the frequency of requests for sanctions.
  </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/17/FrivolousActionFilingsReport.pdf</link>
    </item>
  <item>
    <title>Demographics of Disciplinary Action by the Medical Board of California (2003-2013)</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 9:30:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Patrick Rogers (January 2017). The Medical Board of California protects the health of Californians by ensuring that practicing physicians in the state are licensed and regulated. Conducted at the request of the Medical Board, this report looked at 10 years of disciplinary data to see if there was any relationship between physician race and disciplinary outcomes. Latino/a and Black physicians were both more likely to receive complaints and more likely to see those complaints escalate to investigations. Latino/a physicians were also more likely to see those investigations result in discipline. Asian physicians had a reduced likelihood of receiving complaints, or of those complaints escalating to investigations.
  </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/17/MedicalBoardDemographicsJan17.pdf</link>
    </item>
  <item>
    <title>A Brief History of Major Tax Changes in California, 1979-2015</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 9:20:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Kellie Jean Hogue and Christopher Berger (August 2016) Since Proposition 13 passed in 1978, California has not had another major revamping of its tax system despite a widely acknowledged need for an overhaul. As a result, the state's fiscal health relies disproportionately on personal income tax, and sales and use tax. This paper, which was originally published in an appendix to Controller Betty Yee's "Comprehensive Tax Reform in California: A Contextual Framework," looks at the frequent incremental changes on taxation California has made, including the Legislature considering an average of 245 tax bills per year over the last two decades. 
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/FinalVersion_kjh_10192016ONLINE_Accessible.pdf</link>
</item>
  <item>
    <title>Housing First: How well does it work in ending homelessness?</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 9:55:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>(October 2016) As the Legislature considered a major expansion of Housing First solutions for chronically homeless persons, the Research Bureau gathered experts to discuss the evidence behind Housing First and emerging solutions for the majority of homeless people who are not chronically homeless. 
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/CRBHousingFirst.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Review of the Unlawful Detainer Pilot Program</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 9:50:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>(October 2016). State legislation allowing city attorneys in a pilot program to evict tenants for drug- and weapon-related nuisances began almost two decades ago in California. Four cities currently participate in the program - Long Beach, Los Angeles, Oakland and Sacramento. Under the pilot program city attorney-sponsored evictions are permitted when tenants "create a nuisance on the property by using or allowing the premises to be used" for unlawful firearms or drug activity. In 2015, city attorneys used the program 64 times against 74 tenants, a marked decrease from the 235 times cities used the program in 2011. This report reviews program use by each city and provides tenant demographic information and other data.     
    </description>
    <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/CRB_Unlawful_Detainer_Report_online.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sober Living Homes in California: Options for State and Local Regulation</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 9:50:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Jason MacCannell and Kellie Jean Hogue (October 2016). Under the social model of recovery from substance abuse disorders, the sober living home has become an important resource for persons in recovery in California and elsewhere. Since the law generally treats sober living homes as residences rather than treatment facilities, state and local governments do not require them to carry licenses or impose other regulations outside of the general regulations on housing, zoning and land use. The proliferation of sober living homes in some places has raised concerns that they are being operated more like businesses than homes, impinging on the residential use and character of areas where they are concentrated. This report explores recent efforts to regulate sober living homes at the state and local level, the legal challenges that local ordinances in California have faced and policy options for regulation of these establishments at the state level.     
    </description>
    <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/CRB_SoberLivingReport_2016.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sober Living Homes in California: Options for State and Local Regulation</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 9:05:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Jason MacCannell and Kellie Jean Hogue (October 2016). Under the social model of recovery from substance abuse disorders, the sober living home has become an important resource for persons in recovery in California and elsewhere. Since the law generally treats sober living homes as residences rather than treatment facilities, state and local governments do not require them to carry licenses or impose other regulations outside of the general regulations on housing, zoning and land use. The proliferation of sober living homes in some places has raised concerns that they are being operated more like businesses than homes, impinging on the residential use and character of areas where they are concentrated. This report explores recent efforts to regulate sober living homes at the state and local level, the legal challenges that local ordinances in California have faced and policy options for regulation of these establishments at the state level.    
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/CRB_SoberLivingReport_2016.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Women on Corporate Boards: Increasing in California but Still Underrepresented.</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 2:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Amanda Kimball, Guest Author, and Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (January 2016). In 2014, women represented 13.3 percent of board directors on California's largest company boards, up from 8.8 percent in 2005. The continued underrepresentation of women on California boards is widespread even as it varies significantly across counties and industries. This research brief describes  international, national and California programs to increase the number of women board directors, analyzes women directors by location and industry, and offers options California could undertake to increase women’s representation on corporate boards. 
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/WomenonCorporateBoards_Final.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/16/CRB_CPM_Final.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Veterans' Discharge Paperwork: LGBT Veterans Say Change is Needed.</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 4:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-15-004, September 2015) California is home to the largest number of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender (LGBT) veterans in the country – more than double the next closest state. When these service members left active duty military service, the Department of Defense issued them discharge papers that characterized their military service. For LGBT veterans, discharge papers reflecting outdated gender identities and outdated policies – such as "Don't Ask, Don't Tell" – can cause a loss of access to earned military benefits and services. 
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/15/S-15-004.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Women of Color in California's Legislature.</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 4:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>John Cornelison (S-15-003, August 2015) This analysis traces the path by California women of color to the state Legislature from 1966 – when the first women of color were elected – to today. It provides details about election trends by racial and ethnic groups as well as by party affiliation. This is the second in the Women in Politics series. 
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/15/S-15-003.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Better Serving Those Who Serve: California's LGBT Veterans Speak Out.</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 5:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. and Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (June 2015) Results presented here bring together the experiences and analyses of California leaders in LGBT and veteran communities, including LGBT veterans, service providers, other organizations and spouses. This white paper makes public the policies and programs that a cross-section of LGBT veterans, allies and service organizations recommend to reduce discrimination and expand equal opportunity for LGBT veterans. These suggestions include recommendations for federal, state and local actions gathered at a two-day California Department of Veterans Affairs LGBT veterans leadership forum. Examples include housing accommodations for trauma survivors, nondiscrimination employment protections, cultural sensitivity training, college campus resource centers and an expedited process to upgrade discharge papers that "out" LGBT veterans' sexual orientations or transgender identities. 
    </description>
  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/15/ExecutiveSummary.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Nanotechnology and Society: An Overview.</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>Guest authors: Christine Shearer, Ph.D., Jennifer Rogers-Brown, Ph.D., and Stacey Frederick, Ph.D. CRB contact Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-15-002) This Short Subject provides an introduction to nanotechnology, its potential risks and applications, and current regulation in the United States and California. "Nano" refers to particles and effects scaled at billionths of a meter. Emerging applications hold great promise in many areas, including new ways to treat cancer. Guest authors affiliated with UC Santa Barbara's Center for Nanotechnology and Society. 
    </description>
	<link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/15/15-002.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
    <title>California State Parks: Implementing Recent Recommendations Regarding Peace Officers.</title>
    <pubDate>Thu, 5 Feb 2015 2:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    <description>(15-001, February 2015) This is the third report on California State Parks, prepared at the request of the Senate Natural Resources &amp; Water Committee and the Assembly Water, Parks &amp; Wildlife Committee. It describes how the state could change the peace officer requirements for state park superintendents and state park rangers, and raises questions about the effects of such changes on the structure and culture of the Department of Parks and Recreation. Recent reports by the Little Hoover Commission and the Parks Forward Commission recommended these changes as important steps to transforming DPR into a new operating model built around shared management, innovation, and greater transparency. Previous reports in this series include: California State Parks: A Budget Overview (13-002, December 2013); California State Parks: An Equitable and Sustainable Revenue Strategy (14-001, May 2014)
    </description>
	<link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/15/15-001.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California's Women State Legislators: Historical Trends (1918 to December 1, 2014).</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 1 Dec 2014 3:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>John Cornelison (S-14-023, December 2014) This is the second in the Women in Politics series of short subjects about women officeholders in California. This updated edition was prepared at the request of the California Legislative Women's Caucus, and adds election results through December 1, 2014. This short subject discusses the number and party affiliation of the 147 women elected to California's Legislature since 1918, as well as the effect of term limits enacted by the voters in 1990. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-023.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>MakeHERSpaces: STEM, Girls, and the Maker Movement.</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Pamela Martin, MPPA  (S-14-022, September 2014) Makerspaces in libraries, schools, and museums are places where people apply scientific and engineering principles in a hands-on environment to create things such as robots and 3D models. Since boys are often well-represented in STEM fields, many organizers in the maker movement are attempting to directly engage women and girls and motivate them in a maker environment. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-022.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>An Overview of Men as Informal Caregivers.</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Pamela Martin, MPPA (S-14-021, September 2014) In California, the number of men who provide informal care for loved ones with disabilities is on the rise. As a part of our Healthy Aging Series, this report discusses a few distinct features of male informal caregivers, including the problems of physical and emotional stress, how male caregivers see themselves, and the key role that social networks play.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-021.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California's Women Veterans: Responses to the 2013 Survey.</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 8 Sep 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (14-002, September 2014) This report presents information from the 2013 California Women Veteran Survey. The results suggest there is an opportunity for increased outreach and education among women veteran communities. Most respondents were unaware of all the state’s veteran-related benefits and services to which they are entitled. Some of those who may be eligible for service-connected disability compensation had not filed claims. Many who had not used U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs healthcare reported they did not realize they were eligible. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/14-002.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Researching Oil in California History.</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kathleen Correia, Michael Dolgushkin, and Karen Paige, Guest Authors from California History Section (S-14-020, August 2014) Where can you find historical information about oil in California? The first in a new series spotlighting the State Library's California History Section, this Short Subject features publication, documentary, and visual resources about oil in California as well as some of the Library's ephemera. We also introduce you to a hidden treasure, the California Information File. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-018.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>The Impact of Childcare Needs on Employment and Healthcare. 2013 California Women Veteran Survey.</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 4 Aug 2014 10:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-14-018, July 2014) This Short Subject presents results from the 2013 California Women Veteran Survey, which asked respondents questions about childcare and the effects that childcare needs may have on employment and healthcare decisions. Slightly more than 50 percent of respondents with children under the age of 13 reported using at least one form of childcare. More than 30 percent of respondents with more than one child under 13 indicated that childcare needs had influenced their decision to have certain healthcare services performed, the location of the healthcare they received, and/or whether or not they could even afford healthcare.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-018.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Psychosocial and Economic Health of Older American Indians and Alaskan Natives in California.</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. and Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-14-017, July 2014) This Short Subject is a part of our Healthy Aging Series and employs California Health Interview Survey (CHIS) indicators of mental health, social environment, and economic security to better understand California's older AIANs. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-017.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>State Veteran Benefit Utilization. 2013 California Women Veteran Survey.</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-14-016, June 2014) This Short Subject presents results from the 2013 California Women Veteran Survey, which asked respondents questions about their use and knowledge of a variety of veteran benefits and services offered by the state of California. The two most commonly used state veteran benefits were California Employment Development Department employment assistance and unemployment benefits. Fewer than 15 percent reported using any of the other benefits with which respondents were prompted. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-016.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>Sources, Uses, and Disposal of Water in Hydraulic Fracturing</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. (S-14-014, June 2014) Water is an integral part of hydraulic fracturing, an enhanced technique for oil and gas recovery that has garnered much media attention in recent years. Sources and uses of water vary, depending on the type of event, geographic site, and geologic situation. The second in our series on hydraulic fracturing in California, this Short Subject discusses the role of water in this popular technique: where it comes from, how it is used, the composition of hydraulic fracturing fluids, and what happens to the fluids after the event. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-014.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>Water Conservation in California: State Law and Local Enforcement</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Maeve Roche (S-14-015, June 2014) This Short Subject summarizes current state laws regarding water conservation and provides a review of the water conservation enforcement measures of selected public entities.  
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-015.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Aging and the LGBT Community</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2014 10:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. (S-14-013, June 2014) This Short Subject is a part of our Healthy Aging Series and offers a brief summary of this diverse group's demographic characteristics and looks at aging in the LGBT community through three additional lenses: identity and relationships, social networks, and cultural competence. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-013.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California State Parks: An Equitable and Sustainable Revenue Generation Strategy</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 2 Jun 2014 10:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Jennifer Ruffolo, M.P.P. and Matthew K. Buttice Ph.D. (14-001, May, 2014) This report describes a sustainable and equitable approach to generating revenue in the California state park system. Employing this approach would result in a balance of public funding and earned revenue to support the parks, with revenue targets that could be largely met by collecting low fees from all users. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/14-001.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Psychosocial and Economic Health of Older Asian Pacific Islanders in California</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 5 May 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-14-012) This Short Subject is a part of our Healthy Aging Series and presents information about the mental and economic health of older Asian Pacific Islanders (API). A larger percentage of APIs experienced less social connection in some ways and more economic insecurity than other Californians. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-012.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Housing Instability and Homelessness. 2013 California Women Veteran Survey.</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-14-011) This Short Subject presents results from the 2013 California Women Veteran Survey, which asked respondents questions about experiences with homelessness and housing instability following their separation from the U.S. Armed Forces. Overall, 21 percent of respondents reported experiencing homelessness and 60 percent reported housing instability. Enlisted members and those who reported experiencing sexual harassment/assault, PTSD, or a service-connected disability were all more likely to report experiencing homelessness and/or housing instability. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-011.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Health Information Exchange: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2014 9:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Jaemin Lee and Pamela Martin. (S-14-010) As the Affordable Care Act expands health care benefits to millions of uninsured and underinsured people, lowering costs of care has become a pressing issue. One approach to this problem is to reduce duplicative laboratory tests and prevent medication errors by exchanging health information across different care settings. This brief defines major terminologies associated with health information technology and discusses federal efforts to encourage the adoption of electronic health record (EHR) systems among physicians and hospitals. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-010.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Military Sexual Trauma. 2013 California Women Veteran Survey.</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2014 8:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-14-009) This Short Subject presents results from the 2013 California Women Veteran Survey, which asked respondents questions about the prevalence and aftermath of sexual harassment and assault while serving in the military. Overall, 73 percent of respondents reported sexual harassment and 40 percent reported sexual assault. The majority of respondents who experienced harassment and/or assault did not report the incident(s). Of those who did report incidents of sexual assault, more than 60 percent felt retaliated against and 1 in 5 reported suffering from additional physical or sexual violence. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-009.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Psychosocial and Economic Health of Older Latinos in California</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 8:25:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-14-005) This Short Subject is a part of our Healthy Aging Series and presents information about the mental and economic health of older Latinas and Latinos. California's Latina/o population is aging due to an increase in life expectancy and a larger number of Latina/o baby boomers entering their elderly years. A larger percentage of Latinas and Latinos experienced more psychological distress, less social connection in some ways, and more economic insecurity than other Californians.        
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-005.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Pharmaceuticals in Water: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 8:59:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. (S-14-006) Despite a large volume of scientific research, the definitive risks of active pharmaceutical ingredients to human health are largely unknown. Detection of low-level concentrations of pharmaceuticals and personal care products (PPCPs) in California drinking water has raised interest in finding safe ways to dispose of unwanted, unused medications. Prepared at the request of the Senate Committee on Environmental Quality, this series examines the complex issue of pharmaceuticals in water. This short subject provides an overview of pharmaceuticals in water: points of entry into the water supply, relevant legislation, basic terminology, and regulatory agencies.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-006.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Common Pharmaceuticals in California Water</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 8:59:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. (S-14-007) Despite a large volume of scientific research, the definitive risks of active pharmaceutical ingredients to human health are largely unknown. Detection of low-level concentrations of pharmaceuticals and personal care products (PPCPs) in California drinking water has raised interest in finding safe ways to dispose of unwanted, unused medications. Prepared at the request of the Senate Committee on Environmental Quality, this series examines the complex issue of pharmaceuticals in water. This short subject discusses the impacts of pharmaceuticals in water, methods of detection, and offers a list of pharmaceuticals commonly found in water as well as their potential health effects.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-007.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Reducing Pharmaceuticals in California Water</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 8:59:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Kellie Jean Hogue, Ph.D. (S-14-008) Despite a large volume of scientific research, the definitive risks of active pharmaceutical ingredients to human health are largely unknown. Detection of low-level concentrations of pharmaceuticals and personal care products (PPCPs) in California drinking water has raised interest in finding safe ways to dispose of unwanted, unused medications. Prepared at the request of the Senate Committee on Environmental Quality, this series examines the complex issue of pharmaceuticals in water. This short subject looks at methods for removing pharmaceuticals in water: wastewater treatment technologies, disposal practices, and take-back programs.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-008.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>The Role of Aerospace in California's Economy</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 12:01:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Patrick Rogers (B-14-001) Aerospace is one of the nation's standout industries, and one in which California has enjoyed an outsized role. Over $31 billion in aerospace manufacturing production occurred in California in 2011, representing 6.3 percent of all manufacturing activity in the state. Out of $183 billion in aerospace production in the United States in 2011, California represented 17 percent of that total. New trends point to continued growth in California's aerospace industry, with the recent success of commercial space flight companies such as SpaceX and Scaled Composites building testing and manufacturing facilities in the state.      
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/B-14-001.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California's Women State Legislators</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 8:15:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>John Cornelison (S-14-004) The first in the Women in Politics series of short subjects about women officeholders in California. Prepared at the request of the California Legislative Women's Caucus, this short subject discusses the number and party affiliation of the 139 women elected to California’s Legislature from 1918 to 2013 as well as the effect of term limits enacted by the voters in 1990. Data for the Short Subject can be found at <a href="/crb/14/S-14-004.xlsx">www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-004.xlsx</a> in an Excel spreadsheet.        
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-004.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Hydraulic Fracturing in California: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 4 Mar 2014 9:35:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Pamela Martin, MPPA (S-14-001) Hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, is an enhanced technique for oil and gas recovery that has garnered much media attention in recent years. California has been at the forefront of hydraulic fracturing use for more than 60 years, and has even been the site of several "record fracs" in its time. This Short Subject gives a brief history of this oil and gas recovery technique, as well as some of the major landmarks of federal and state oversight in this state.       
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-001.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Psychosocial and Economic Health of Older Nonpartnered Women in California</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 3 Mar 2014 9:31:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-14-003) This Short Subject is a part of our Healthy Aging Series and presents information about the mental and economic health of older, nonpartnered women. A larger percentage of older nonpartnered women experienced more psychological distress, less social connection in some ways, and more economic insecurity than partnered women.      
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-003.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Psychosocial and Economic Health of Older African Americans in California</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 9:08:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-14-002) Another in our Healthy Aging Series (see below), this Short Subject presents information about indicators that may be associated with the shorter lifespans of older African Americans in California. A larger percentage of older African Americans experienced more psychological distress, less social connection in some ways, and more economic insecurity than all other older Californians.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/14/S-14-002.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Californians in Media Occupations: Representation and Income Parity</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 9:42:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-13-021) Another in our California Women and Girls Series, this Short Subject presents demographic information about Californians in media occupations, describes the representation of women and men in each occupation, and compares their median personal incomes to their representation. Where only one of the studied occupations exhibits parity in both representation and income, most of the occupations have a disparity between women and men's representation and incomes.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-021.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California State Parks: A Budget Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 10:05:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. and Jennifer Ruffolo, M.P.P. (13-002) Prepared at the request of the Senate Natural Resources and Water Committee and the Assembly Water Parks and Wildlife Committee, the report reviews the Department of Parks and Recreation’s expenditures over the last 20 years. Funding for support of the state park system has increased although the proportion of General Fund declined, as did reliance on fee revenue. Most of the growth in the Department's budget is attributable to the growth in special funds. The study finds that the most promising source of additional funding for the state park system may be park-generated revenue.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/13-002.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California's Gender Gap in STEM Education and Employment</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2013 10:34:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. and Patrick Rogers (S-13-019, November, 2013) California is a national and global leader in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM), both for education and employment. This position has benefited the state greatly. However, there is a gender gap in educational attainment and employment in STEM fields. Men receive STEM degrees and are employed in STEM fields at a higher rate than women. This Short Subject provides a first look at the differences between men and women in educational attainment and employment in STEM fields in California.     
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-019.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Immigration Reform and Unauthorized Women Immigrants in California</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 OCt 2013 9:05:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>It is estimated that 2.6 million undocumented immigrants currently reside in California. This represents a quarter of all undocumented immigrants in the country as a whole. Of those, approximately 34% are women and another 13% are children under the age of 18. This Short Subject provides a review of the path to citizenship currently being considered by the federal government, and looks at its expected impact on women undocumented immigrants and their children.    
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-018.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Farmworkers in California: A Brief Introduction</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 1 Oct 2013 11:28:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>While California is one of the largest agricultural producing regions in the world, farmworkers in the state face a number of disadvantages. Farmworkers in California are at higher risk for living in poverty and are less likely to have health insurance than are the population as a whole. This Short Subject provides a brief overview of the demographic characteristics and geographic distribution of the nearly 300,000 farmworkers in California.    
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-017.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California Higher Education: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 3 Sep 2013 09:09:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Fourth in our CA Women and Girls Series, this Short Subject presents information about the roughly 3 million people enrolled in California institutions of higher education. It presents information about Californians' participation in higher education, maps participation by county, and identifies the Bachelor's degrees earned most frequently by recent graduates.   
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-016.pdf</link>
</item>		
<item>
      <title>California Women and Incarceration: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 5 Aug 2013 09:49:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Melissa M. Barker, Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D., and Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (S-13-015) Third in our CA Women and Girls Series, this Short Subject compares the number of incarcerated women in California over time, disaggregates 2012 data according to demographic and geographic information, and offers a brief discussion about California women and realignment. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-015.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>The Minimum Wage in California and the U.S.: Current and Historical Practice</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 1:03:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Patrick Rogers and Chris Berger (S-13-014) The first in a new series of Short Subjects on the topic, The Minimum Wage in California and the U.S.: Current and Historical Practice covers the development of minimum wage laws in the country and provides a comparison of wage rates across U.S. states. California’s minimum wage has historically tracked closely with the federal rate, and is currently approximately 110% of the federal wage. California law also provides additional protections for tipped workers, preventing the inclusion of tips in calculations of wage rates. There have also been an increasing number of municipalities establishing higher minimum wage rates on their own, and passing living wage laws, which protect employees of business that contract with the city or county government. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-014.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>The TACPA Program: A Review of Current Structure and Potential Alternatives</title>
      <pubDate>Thur, 18 Jul 2013 04:07:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Pamela Martin, MPPA and Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (B-13-001) This brief report provides background information on the Target Area Contract Preference Act (TACPA) program, identifies potential problems with the current structure of the program, and presents an analysis of potential alternative eligibility rules aimed at overcoming the loss of two criteria indicators at the state-mandated block-group level.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/B-13-001.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
	<title>The Technical Appendix to the TACPA Program</title>
      <pubDate>Thur, 31 May 2013 10:22:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The Technical Appendix (M-13-002) provides a detailed overview of the TACPA analysis conducted by the California Research Bureau.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/M-13-002.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California Women and Employment: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Thur, 18 Jun 2013 4:45:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-13-013) The second in our series of Short Subjects on election policy (see first entry Voter Identification: A Brief Overview below). A 2012 review of state voter lists found that approximately 24 million voter registrations in the United States are inaccurate or no longer valid. This Short Subject provides an overview of the procedures election officials use to collect and manage databases of registered voters. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-013.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>California Women and Employment: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Thur, 31 May 2013 3:17:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Sun Young Kim, Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D., and Matthew K. Buttice (S-13-012) Second in our CA Women and Girls Series (see below Women and Education), this Short Subject presents information about the nearly 15 million women and girls in California age 16 and over. Despite comprising 46 percent of the labor force, this group earned 39 percent of total personal income in California during 2011 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-012.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>California Men and Healthy Aging</title>
      <pubDate>Thur, 31 May 2013 09:49:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. and Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-13-011) Sixth in our Healthy Aging Series (see below), this Short Subject presents information about the approximately 4.8 million men in California who are age 50 or over. Though most of these California men have health insurance, 14 percent of preretirement age and 4 percent of retirement age men report that they could not see a doctor in the past year because of the cost. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-011.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>Californians 65 and over in the Labor Force</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 12:14:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice and Ph.D. Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D., (S-13-010) Fifth in our Healthy Aging Series (see below), this Short Subject presents information about the approximately 4.2 million Californians who are age 65 or over. Since 1980, whether because of longer life spans, increased financial need, or for other reasons, the labor force participation of Californians who are ages 65+ has increased by 6 to 7 percentage points. Orange, Mendocino, and Marin counties have the largest percentage of their 65+ population in the labor force. The lowest participation rates are found in Trinity, Imperial, and Amador counties. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-010.pdf</link>
</item>	
<item>
      <title>California Women and Education: An Overview</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2013 02:49:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. and Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D. (S-13-009) This Short Subject presents degree attainment trends for California women since the 1960s, compares these to national rates, breaks out rates according to race/ethnic category, and offers a brief discussion. Recent U.S. Census data suggest that California may fall short of national educational attainment rates for women when compared to attainment rates of women nationally. While California women have higher levels of education than they did in prior years, disparities across different race/ethnic backgrounds remain. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-009.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>City-Attorney-Sponsored Unlawful Detainer in California Part I: Mandated Information 2013 Report to the Legislature</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 12:15:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D. (13-001) AB1384 (Havice, Ch.613, Stats. 1997-1998) established the legal capacity for city attorneys in five cities to sue for unlawful detainer (an eviction suit) when property owners were either unwilling or unable to evict a tenant arrested for drug or weapons crimes. The program was designed to facilitate the effective and efficient removal of criminals from neighborhoods. This report was produced in response to AB 530 (Krekorian, Ch. 244, Stats. 2009-2010), requiring CRB to evaluate the pilot Unlawful Detainer program. Current reporting requirements and practices make it difficult to assess the overall merits of the UD pilot programs. Few UD notices were filed in court by city attorneys, a finding consistent with CRB's first report. Weapon-related UD notices appear to be about twice as likely to lead to subsequent court action as drug-related notices, although many more drug-related notices were issued.  
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/13-001.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Testimony Before the Assembly Committee on Housing and Community Development and the Assembly Committee on Veterans Affairs, March 20, 2013</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 03:06:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. This document provides the written testimony submitted to the the joint Assembly committees as background information about homeless veterans in California. Oral comments were a condensed version of this testimony. In addition, please see the relevant brief about California's Women Veterans and Homelessness at http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-011.pdf. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/13-020.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Military Families and Child Care Needs in California</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 04:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton, (S-13-008) California is home to approximately 106,000 military children (children with at least one parent in the Armed Forces). The Department of Defense (DOD) attempts to provide child care to 80 percent of military children aged 13 or less. The other 20 percent of child care is provided through community providers. In some areas of California, there is not enough community child care to bridge this gap. This brief explores the child care needs of California's military families, the issues around licensing DOD-apporved child care versus California state approved child care and the costs of child care for military families. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-008.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Bagley-Keene Open Meeting Act: General Guidelines</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 04:25:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D., Patrick Rogers, (CRB S-13-003) This fact sheet provides basic information about how to include the public in Bagley-Keene eligible meetings and when Bagley-Keene applies. It should serve as an informal compendium of the unabridged law. This is the fourth in CRB's series of short subjects about open government.  
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-003.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California Women and Healthy Aging</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 11:37:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Matthew K. Buttice, Ph.D., Tonya D. Lindsey, Ph.D., (S-13-002) This overview presents some of the health issues California women ages 50 and over experience, compares them to women nationally, reports preventative strategies some employ, and discusses how health issues may differ for California women according to their race/ethnic categories. Despite that 86 percent of California women ages 50-64 and 99 percent of those 65 and older have healthcare coverage, some report not going to the doctor because of the cost.  
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-002.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Military Spouses and Professional Licensing</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 10:22:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton, (S-13-001) Military spouses face a special burden when it comes to obtaining and maintaining professional licenses. This brief explores the issues military spouses face and offers several options the State may take to reduce these burdens.   
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/13/S-13-001.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>California's Women Veterans and Homelessness</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 11:43:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton, (S-12-011) CRB surveyed over 800 women veterans about their housing status and found that one in seven had experienced homelessness and one in three had experienced unstable housing. This brief sheds some light on the extent of homelessness and the precursors to unstable housing for women veterans in California. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-011.pdf</link>
</item>

	

<item>
      <title>HIV/AIDS in California: 2012 Update</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 09:17:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. Using the latest data from the Center for Disease Control and the California Department of Public Health, CRB finds 1 in 268 Californian's is currently infected with HIV. The rate of infection differs significantly between racial groups. The Black population in California experiences infection at three times the rate of White's in California and nine times that of the state's Asian-American population. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-012.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Voter Identification: A Brief Introduction</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 13:38:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The first in a CRB series of Short Subjects on election policy. This Short Subject provides an overview of voter ID including current laws, pros and cons, court challenges, and impact on the November 2012 elections.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/Voter_ID_Short_Subject_FINAL.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans and Military Sexual Trauma (MST)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 4 Oct 2012 07:46:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. Provides an overview of military women’s experiences with MST as reported in a confidential survey after they left the service. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-004.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans and Mental Health</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 4 Oct 2012 07:46:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. Provides an overview of women veterans mental health needs and costs of providing mental health services to this population. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-005.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans and Employment</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 4 Oct 2012 07:46:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. Provides an overview of women veterans' employment prospects and unemployment statistics in CA. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-007.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans and Benefit Utilization</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 4 Oct 2012 07:46:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. Provides an overview of women veterans’ pattern of state benefit utilization. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-008.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans at a Glance</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 4 Oct 2012 07:46:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Rebecca E. Blanton. Provides an overview key statistics about women veterans in CA as of October 2012. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-009.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Characteristics of Suicide: Data from California's Electronic Violent Death Reporting System.  
</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Jason Van Court. Provides an overview of suicides in CA for 2009, the most recently available data. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-005.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Characteristics of Homicide: Data from California's Electronic Violent Death Reporting System. 
</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Jason Van Court. Provides an overview of homicides in CA for 2009, the most recently available data. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-11-006.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>Understanding Violent Deaths in California.</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Jason Van Court. Provides an overview of the California Electronic Violent Death Reporting System (CalEVDRS) system and the information it contains. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-11-002.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Principles of Open Government: Transparency, Participation and Collaboration</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The third in CRB's series of short subjects about issues impacting open government initiatives. This short subject discusses the three principles that underlie open government initiatives: Transparency, Participation and Collaboration.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-003.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Open-source Software: Value, Cost, and Supporting Open Government</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 7 Aug 2012 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The second in CRB's series of short subjects about issues impacting open government initiatives. This short subject defines open-source software and explains its value, cost, and how it can support open government.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-02.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Public-use Data: Safe, Secure, and Supporting Open Government</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 7 Aug 2012 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The first in CRB's series of short subjects about issues impacting open government initiatives. This short subjects defines public-use data and explains how they can be safe, secure, and support open government.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/S-12-01.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California's Women Veterans: Responses to the 2011 Survey</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 2 Jul 2012 7:49:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>CRB, at the request of CalVet and the Commission on the Status of Women, surveyed California’s women veterans to find out what they currently need, what they needed at the time they transitioned from the military, and what are their sociodemographics. This report presents the findings of that survey. Women veterans told us they need help finding a job when they leave the service and that they currently want physical and mental health care. The needs for women-specific and senior-specific services are growing needs in the women veterans community as well."
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/12-004.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Open-source Software: Value, Cost, and Supporting Open Government</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 9:52:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The second in CRB's series of short subjects about issues impacting open government initiatives. This short subject defines open-source software and explains its value, cost, and how it can support open government.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/Open_Source_ShortSubjects_Final.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Public-use Data: Safe, Secure, and Supporting Open Government</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 9:52:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The first in CRB's series of short subjects about issues impacting open government initiatives. This short subjects defines public-use data and explains how they can be safe, secure, and support open government.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/PublicuseData_ShortSubjects _ Final.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans: Response to the 2011 Survey: Preliminary Report</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 8:28:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>California has the largest number (167,000) and greatest proportion (9.5 percent) of female veterans in the country. Currently, who these women are and what they need is generally unknown. The California Research Bureau, along with CalVet and the Commission on the Status of Women, conducted a survey of nearly 900 women veterans in California to find out who they are and what they need. This report presents the preliminary findings from the 2011 survey of these women veterans.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/FINAL_REPORT.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>White Paper: Interagency Council on Veterans, February 22-23, 2012</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 14:18:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Governor Edmund G. (“Jerry”) Brown established the Interagency Council on Veterans (ICV) in order to coordinate state-level activities to improve services and outreach for veterans. Participants of the ICV met in February 2012 over two days to discuss the service needs, gaps and obstacles in service and outline potential next steps for improving services to veterans. This paper analyzes the contents of the meeting discussions and presents key findings from that analysis. Participants in the ICV identified the need for funding, increasing data sharing and data capture, improving transition programs and increasing public outreach as critical needs for the veteran community.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/WhitePaperICV.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California Charter Oversight: Key Elements and Actual Costs</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 10:35:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Charter schools are overseen by authorizers. In California, an authorizer is generally a school district, but may be a county office of education or the State Board of Education. As of June 2011, California had 293 authorizers overseeing 911 charter schools. In SB537 (Ch.650, Stats. of 2007) the Legislature mandated the California Research Bureau review the practices of authorizers in California, examine best practices in authorizing, review the current funding structure for authorizers and submit to the Legislature a report on key elements and actual costs of charter authorizing. This report provides CRB’s findings from its investigation of California’s authorizers. Additionally, it provides several options to the Legislature for improving charter oversight.
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/12/12-001.pdf</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>Unlawful Detainer Pilot Program: A Report to the California Legislature</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2011 10:35:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>AB1384 (Havice, Ch.613, Stats. 1997-1998) established the legal capacity for city attorneys in five cities to sue for unlawful detainer (an eviction suit) when property owners were either unwilling or unable to evict a tenant arrested for drug or weapons crimes. The program was designed to facilitate the effective and efficient removal of criminals from neighborhoods. This report was produced in response to AB 530 (Krekorian, Ch. 244, Stats. 2009-2010), requiring CRB to evaluate the pilot Unlawful Detainer program. CRB used the data reported by three pilot sites as mandated in Civil Code sections 3485 and 3486. The data showed that the program was utilized approximately 300 times across the three cities that opted to participate in the pilot program in 2010. The most common result of an unlawful detainer suit was that the tenant vacated the property prior to the full prosecution of the suit.</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/11/Unlawful_Detainer_Pilot_Program_Report.pdf</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>March 2011 Women's History Month Calendar</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 11:45:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Coastal Aquatic Invasive Species (CAIS) increasingly threaten California’s coastal estuarine and marine habitats. With no natural predators, these non-native species become abundant, resulting in costly, negative impacts on infrastructure, human health, and natural ecosystems. Seeking assistance in implementing the California Aquatic Invasive Species Management Plan, the Senate Natural Resources and Water Committee, requested that the California Research Bureau craft a framework for understanding the challenges that coastal aquatic invasive species create for California. In the resulting report, Managing Coastal Aquatic Invasive Species in California: Existing Policies and Policy Gaps, CRB Senior Environmental Policy Fellow, Adrianna Muir, Ph.D. highlights the CAIS policy and management challenges facing California. The report focuses on opportunities for improvement over six general policy categories (Authority, Prevention, Research, Control, Implementation, and Coordination) and addresses the vectors, or pathways, through which invasive species are introduced. 
</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/11/11-002.pdf</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>Managing Coastal Aquatic Invasive Species in California: Existing Policies and Policy Gaps</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 11:45:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Coastal Aquatic Invasive Species (CAIS) increasingly threaten California’s coastal estuarine and marine habitats. With no natural predators, these non-native species become abundant, resulting in costly, negative impacts on infrastructure, human health, and natural ecosystems. Seeking assistance in implementing the California Aquatic Invasive Species Management Plan, the Senate Natural Resources and Water Committee, requested that the California Research Bureau craft a framework for understanding the challenges that coastal aquatic invasive species create for California. In the resulting report, Managing Coastal Aquatic Invasive Species in California: Existing Policies and Policy Gaps, CRB Senior Environmental Policy Fellow, Adrianna Muir, Ph.D. highlights the CAIS policy and management challenges facing California. The report focuses on opportunities for improvement over six general policy categories (Authority, Prevention, Research, Control, Implementation, and Coordination) and addresses the vectors, or pathways, through which invasive species are introduced.</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/11/11-001.pdf</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>Healthcare Reform: Selected Topic Seminars</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 10:15:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Key issues in achieving universal healthcare coverage are the affordability of and lack of enrollment in health insurance. A recent report from the Commonwealth Fund’s Commission on a High Performance Health System concludes “the failure to provide continuous, affordable coverage that ensures access and financial protection to everyone in the United States contributes to the poor performance of the health system.”</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/10/WomenVeteransBrieflyStated.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>California’s Women Veterans: The Challenges and Needs of Those Who Served</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 10:50:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Women represent over 15 percent of the active duty and reserve forces of the military, and make up over 220,000 of the 1.8 million troops serving in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom (Afghanistan) – the largest wartime deployment for U.S. women. Following their military service, often in combat conditions, women are returning to their roles as private citizens – wives, mothers, caregivers, workers – in unprecedented numbers. Women veterans share many of the short- and long-term physical and emotional consequences and needs that their male counterparts face as a result of serving their country. In addition, they have unique experiences and needs as female veterans. The report describes the state’s more than 167,000 women veterans (eight percent of the total veteran population); it identifies the challenges these veterans face, the primary services they need, and barriers they encounter. This report also explains the federal, state, and local service delivery structures that provide benefits and services to veterans, and provides additional resource materials.</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/09/09-009.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Individual Mandate: A Background Report</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 7:50:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Over 46 million Americans are without healthcare coverage. The number of uninsured is increasing with the growth of unemployment and stagnation of employer-based coverage. Healthcare cost growth continues to outpace growth in wages. The individual mandate is a policy option that could significantly reduce the number of uninsured in the United States and lead to universal health care coverage. An individual mandate would require every citizen to obtain health insurance, be it through an employer, an individual plan, a purchasing pool, or a public plan. This report will discuss how such a mandate could work, what it would cost. It also will review the pros and cons of the individual mandate as well as the availability, affordability and enforcement that would come from such a mandate.</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/09/09-007.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Foreclosures 2009 Q1</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 7:50:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The California Foreclosure Watch is a series of quarterly briefs prepared for the Assembly Banking &amp; Finance Committee. CRB’s latest Foreclosure Watch features Q4 2008 data and a new state forecast.</description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/09/foreclosures09Q1BrieflyStated.pdf</link>
</item>
<item>
      <title>The Careers Project</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 5 Mar 2009 16:45:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The Careers Project examined the preparation all students in public middle and high schools receive to explore career options and the relationship between that preparation and California’s state and regional economies. The California Research Bureau undertook this research at the request of a bipartisan group of 11 members of the California Legislature, with funding support from the James Irvine Foundation. The study consisted of three distinct phases: 
1. A statewide survey of middle and high school counselors and principals. 
2. An economic analysis and survey of representatives of business and industry in California.
3. School focus groups. 
	  </description>
	  <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/CRBReports.html</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>A Briefing on Health Technology Assessment (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 15:50:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The United States spends a much higher percentage of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) on healthcare than any other country. Nearly 50 percent of the increase in healthcare costs is attributable to the introduction of new technologies in the practice of medicine. However the rapid introduction of new technologies has not been accompanied by an improvement in health outcomes, suggesting the need to review the effectiveness of these investments. This report describes the process of assessing health technology and identifies national and state agencies and organizations that currently engage in health technology assessment. Finally, the report discusses a proposal to create a centralized body dedicated to the formal scrutiny of innovative (and existing) healthcare technologies and services.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-019.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Where are State Funds Spent? The Distribution of Spending Across California Regions (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 10:45:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>What does the geographic distribution of state spending look like? Are there regions of the state that receive more than their “fair share” of state funds? How is a region’s “fair share” defined and calculated? This report examines the geographic distribution of state spending across nine regions: the San Francisco Bay Area, Central Coast, Far North, Inland Empire, San Joaquin Valley, Sacramento Metro, San Diego, Sierras and South Coast. State expenditures are presented for major program areas such as health, education, public assistance, social services, and transportation. (The same fiscal year, FY 2002-03, is used wherever possible.) The many detailed tables provide a new perspective on state expenditures, one that has not been previously analyzed.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-017.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>County Probation Camps and Ranches for Juvenile Offenders (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 14:12:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>This report, which was requested by Assembly Member Jose Solorio, Chair of the Public Safety Committee, examines California’s county camps and ranches for juvenile offenders in the context of recent reforms of the state’s juvenile justice system. There are different models of county probation camps, including conventional camps, wilderness camps, military (boot camps), and small residential treatment facilities (known as the Missouri model). We describe the different models as implemented by California counties, with information about length of stay requirements and treatment options. When possible, we also describe the educational and vocational requirements and programs provided by the camps, and examine the availability of health and mental health services. </description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-016.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Physician Misconduct and Public Disclosure Practices at the Medical Board of California (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 5 Nov 2008 11:46:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>This report explores current Medical Board of California public disclosure laws, regulations and practices; and presents policy options for improving public access to information about physicians in support of the MBC’s public protection mandate. The report presents new statistical findings on physician attributes associated with higher odds of facing formal disciplinary charges. Additionally, we review academic research on the incidence of medical errors, which suggests that patients harmed by negligent or incompetent care rarely file lawsuits or formal complaints against their caregivers. We present a number of policy options for expanding public disclosure about California physicians and enhancing the MBC’s public outreach program. This report was mandated by SB 1438 (Chapter 223, Statutes of 2006), sponsored by Senator Figueroa.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-015.pdf</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>Child Care Funding Sources for California School Districts (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 15:05:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>School districts are central players in the child care delivery system: they operate a mix of child care centers and programs, serve a range of children of different ages, and fund their programs from a variety of federal, state, and local sources. This report provides a range of programmatic and fiscal information about the federal and state funding sources for child care that are available to California's K-12 public school districts. The focus is on funding that pays for basic care and supervision, or what is considered the child care program "slot" or space. Assembly Member Mark Leno requested that CRB compile this information to assist school districts throughout the state, in addition to policymakers.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-014.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>The National Housing Crisis and its Impact on California—Conference Presentations</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 15:40:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>On September 18, 2008, the California Research Bureau partnered with the Public Policy Institute of California (PPIC) to present a conference on the national housing crisis and its impact on California. The morning presentations examined the scale of the crisis, economic forecasts, and trends in home prices and foreclosures. Speakers in the afternoon discussed removing barriers to home ownership, the crisis in credit availability, new federal and state laws, and policies to mitigate the risk that vacant foreclosed homes will contribute to blight and crime. The CRB’s work in this policy area is in response to a request from the Assembly Banking Committee.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/foreclosure.html</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>Health Information Technology-Electronic Health Records: A Primer (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2008 15:20:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Achieving universal health care coverage will require significant changes in the health care system. There is an expectation that widespread adoption of Health Information Technology-Electronic Medical Records will play an important role in transforming the delivery of health care by improving the quality of care and reducing costs. However physicians lack an incentive to invest since the benefits accrue largely to insurance companies and health care plans. The role of federal and state governments in establishing standards and providing financial resources for expansion of health information technology is another issue of importance. This background paper reviews and summarizes many of the issues that providers, payers and government will have to address in incorporating health information technology into the health care delivery system.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-013.pdf</link>
</item>


<item>
      <title>Estimated Water Use on Large Projects in 2004-2006 (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 14:30:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Senator Sheila Kuehl asked the California Research Bureau (CRB) to provide analysis about the impact of two bills enacted in 2001: SB 221 and SB 610. These bills require local agencies to determine that a reasonably reliable water supply exists before approving new large projects including residential subdivisions with over 500 units, and large industrial and commercial projects. CRB estimated the number of subdivisions and dwelling units that were subject to these two bills from 2004 to 2006, estimated the amount of water used by these subdivisions and evaluated how the estimates would have changed if the law were lowered to apply to subdivisions with over 250 units. CRB also estimated water use in large industrial and commercial projects.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-012.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Financing Delta Improvements and Environmental Mitigation (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 16:30:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Resolution of the Delta's water supply, water quality, and fish problems may involve building various structures, possibly including gates, pumps, canals, levees, and dams, and undertaking landscaping rearrangements to improve habitat for several species of flora and fauna. Resolution also involves changing water flow regimes in ways that would make more or less water, but probably less, available for human uses. This work and these changes will cost serious money. Cost estimates for many of these actions have not yet been developed.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-011.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Homeless Youth: Bibliography and Resources (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 16:30:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The CRB and the California Council on Youth Relations, with support from The California Wellness Foundation, are conducting a major research and policy initiative to identify and bring to the attention of state policymakers the serious issues facing homeless youth in California. This report is a resource document and includes an annotated bibliography drawn from a wide range of academic and program-based research, agendas from CRB public policy seminars held over the last year, and contact information for the seminar presenters.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-010.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Security and Privacy Recommendations for Government-Issued Identity Documents Using Radio Frequency Identification Tags or Other Technologies (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 15:05:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>This report was produced in response to a request from Senator S. Joseph Simitian to provide policy recommendations regarding the use of technology-enhanced, government-issued identification documents. After examining the technical and personal security issues and concerns of these next-generation documents and their accompanying electronic infrastructure, assembling an expert advisory panel, and holding a series of public meetings to obtain input, CRB developed the report's recommendations for the selection and use of these technologies by state and local government agencies.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-008.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Hepatitis C: Public Policy Implications of a Silent Virus (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 12:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>More than 5 million people nationwide are infected with HCV; including 600,000 Californians. Due to the insidious nature of the virus, it is believed that fewer than half of them know they are infected. For many individuals the infection is discovered after the development of advanced liver disease, leaving some patients with no treatment option other than a liver transplant. Even when discovered early, the costly, often debilitating treatment process is successful in less than half the patients who are treated. The paper begins with a brief overview of the discovery of a hepatitis-related virus in the blood supply and how the cause of the virus, now known as hepatitis C, was discovered. The overview continues with detailed discussions of the risk factors and sources of infection for HCV, the diagnostic process, pathways of disease progression, and potential treatment options. A review of the prevalence and the direct and indirect costs associated with HCV are also included. The second half of the paper contains detailed discussions of the policy issues related to HCV including disease tracking and surveillance, a historical timeline of prevention and control efforts, workers compensation and presumptive infection, and access to care and insurance. </description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-009.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Foreclosures in California: The current housing crisis is more severe than previous corrections (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 15:05:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The Chair of the Assembly Banking Committee requested that the California Research Bureau prepare estimates of the number of housing foreclosures in California. Our estimate of the number of housing foreclosures in the State during the current cycle (2006 – 09), varies from 170,000 to 434,000. Foreclosures will affect between 3.0 and 7.8 percent of all homeowners with mortgages (depending on the underlying assumptions, as discussed in the Note). CRB also presents a range of estimates for metropolitan counties. As the credit and housing crisis plays out, CRB plans to update this Note and publish similar quarterly estimates throughout the year.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-006.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Voices from the Street: A Survey of Homeless Youth by Their Peers (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 11:05:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Homeless youth are a hidden population. To shed light on this group of vulnerable young people, CRB conducted a survey in which homeless and formerly homeless youth completed over 200 interviews with their homeless peers across the state. The youth interviewed describe their experiences – how they became homeless, what life on the street is like, their interactions with police, their education and aspirations, their mental health experiences, how they go about getting help – the services they need, and the changes they would like to see happen in policy or law. The majority come from the hardest-to-reach and least-studied homeless populations: youth who sleep on the streets or in cars, squat in abandoned buildings, or "couch-surf." Most left their families because of violence or abuse or were kicked out, and many are surviving on the streets in the neighborhoods in which they grew up. This report presents the survey responses and findings. It is a primary component of the California Homeless Youth Project, a major research and policy initiative undertaken by the CRB and California Council on Youth Relations, with support from The California Wellness Foundation, to bring attention to the serious issues facing homeless youth in the state.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-004.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Student Loans for Higher Education (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 16:10:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>Student loans are a rapidly growing $85 billion a year industry fueled by the substantial higher economic returns associated with a college education, increased demand from students and their parents, and grant and scholarship funds that have not kept pace with rising school tuition and fees. This report describes federally subsidized and guaranteed loans, examines the private student loan industry, and discusses issues relating to student debt and financial counseling. We describe practices that have led to allegations and findings of fraud and abuse in the student loan system, and recent federal and state legislative and administrative responses. The report was requested by Assemblymember Sally Lieber in order to better understand the national student loan scandal and responses to it.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-002.pdf</link>
</item>

<item>
      <title>Actuarially Speaking: A Plain Language Summary of Actuarial Methods and Practices for Public Employee Pension and Other Post-Employment Benefits (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 14:35:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>In January 2008, the California Public Employee Post-Employment Benefits Commission issued recommendations to address the costs of providing public employee pension and retiree health benefits. Several of the Commission’s recommendations -- and provisions of legislation introduced to implement those recommendations (SB 1123, Wiggins) -- address actuarial practices used to determine funding levels for pension and retiree health benefits. Because actuarial methods are a unique and somewhat complex form of financial accounting, this “plain language” summary was developed to serve as a reference guide for policy makers, government employers, pension and health plan administrators, and members of the general public interested in the topic.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-003.pdf</link>
</item>
	
	
<item>
      <title>Ex Parte Communications: The Law and Practices at Six California Boards and Commissions (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 10:03:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>This report, which was requested by Assemblymember Loni Hancock, Chair of the Natural Resources Committee, examines the legal limitations on ex parte communications between board commissioners and interested outsiders on the following state boards and commissions: California Air Resources Board, Integrated Waste Management Board, State Water Resources Control Board, California Energy Resources Conservation and Development Commission (Energy Commission), Public Utilities Commission, California Coastal Commission. Ex parte communications are made in private between an interested party in a decision-making process and an official in a decision-making position. Because they can introduce an element of bias in a decision-making process and violate basic due process requirements, state law generally requires that the involved officials publicly disclose ex parte communications in an open meeting. However the legal requirements and practices for the six boards and commissions analyzed for this report vary, and the public disclosure process evidenced in their meeting minutes is uneven.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/08/08-001.pdf</link>
</item>
	
<item>
      <title>California Research Bureau Public Retirement System Survey (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 10:47:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>In response to ongoing concerns about the cost of providing post-employment benefits to public employees, the California Public Employee Post-Employment Benefits Commission requested that the California Research Bureau conduct a survey of the state's public retirement systems to identify the amount of pension benefits that remain unfunded. The survey found that despite $63.5 billion in unfunded public employee pension liabilities, public retirement systems are recovering from the impact of the downturn in the financial markets that occurred in the early 2000s. California public retirement systems' aggregate funded ratio (the total assets that the systems hold in trust funds to pay benefits relative to the expected cost of benefits they are obligated to pay) is higher than it was in the early- to mid-1990s.
</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/07/07-014.pdf</link>
    </item>
	
	<item>
      <title>Homeless and Runaway Youth: Selected Resources: PRELIMINARY REPORT (PDF)</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 5 Dec 2007 12:00:00 PST</pubDate>
      <description>The CRB and the California Council on Youth Relations, with support from The California Wellness Foundation, are conducting a major research and policy initiative to identify and bring to the attention of state policymakers the serious issues facing homeless youth in California. The project entails several research components whose findings are being presented in CRB reports and a series of public policy seminars. We have also identified and reviewed a wide range of academic and program-based research about homeless youth. This annotated bibliography of selected resources is presented here as a work in progress; new materials are being identified and added on an ongoing basis. Once the Homeless and Runaway Youth Project is completed in the Spring of 2008, the final bibliography will be published as a CRB report.</description>
      <link>http://www.library.ca.gov/crb/07/07-099.pdf</link>
    </item>
    

	
  </channel>
</rss>
